Rilson Almeida

Proactive System Analyst with over 30 years of experience. A confident communicator with natural analytical abilities, adept in web development methodologies (focusing on Django/Python and React). Areas of interest: Information Security, Machine Learning and Data Science.

∢ rilson.almeida@gmail.com

+55 71 991182941

 Jd Federacao, 334, Salvador, Bahia 40231060

WORK HISTORY

December 2004 to Current

TRE/BA

TRIBUNAL REGIONAL ELEITORAL DA BAHIA, Salvador

- Holds position of Cybersecurity Advisory at TRE/BA Information Technology Secretariat
- Member of TRE Information Security Committee

April 2015 to October 2015

Systems Analyst, RENACH System Consultant **SOLUTIS TECNOLOGIAS LTDA**, Salvador

- Systems Analyst in DETRAN/BA, RENACH System Consultant (using Unisys EAE/Enterprise Application Environment).
- Continuously improved and refined capabilities in systems analysis to increase productivity.

April 2009 to April 2015

Systems Analyst INDRA/POLITEC TECNOLOGIA DA INFORMAÇÃO LTDA, Salvador

- DETRAN/BA, RENACH System Consultant (EAE)
- Development and Implementation of RENACH SDD Module "Suspension of Right to Drive") coordinated team that implemented SDD module, integrated to RENACH, with significant returns
- Delivered projects in line with company values, ensuring complete compliance with IT requirements.

February 2007 to March 2009

System Analyst, Coordinator, Consultant

SKILLS

- TECHNICAL KNOWLEDEGE/METHODOLOGIES
- Python (Django/Flask)
- Information security
- Systems analysis
- Data Science (Python, R, Tableau, Jupyter, GoogleColab)
- Java, Spring Framework, JWT, JPA, Hibernate, Ionic
- MVC/ORM
- HTML 5/CSS 3/JavaScript
- React.JS, React Native, Vue.JS

EDUCATION

July 1990

Bachelor of Science Data Processing Federal University of Bahia (UFBA,

Salvador, BR

LANGUAGES

English

Advanced

Sistema Nacional de Gravames, Montreal, Salvador

- Implemented National System of Gravames module of RENAVAM system, using LINC-II (4th Generation Language) in Unisys NX-520 environment, RENACH (EAE tool)
- Gravame is record made in National Transit System (SNT) to indicate that vehicle is linked to some contract, such as financing.

May 2003 to July 2003

Systems Analyst
Bradesco, Salvador

 Banking Automation area of Banco Bradesco (Microinformatics agency environment until September 2001), and from then on, with IBM mainframe, participating in Baneb/Bradesco migration of LV (Vehicle Licensing) and AR systems (Collection), using tools: Natural, Cobol Cics / DB2, Cobol II, JCL, Change Man

January 1997 to January 2001

Systems Analyst
BANEB - BANCO DO ESTADO DA BAHIA S/A, CEV
Treinamentos, Salvador

- Banking Automation (agency environment), covering 8- 16-bit boxes and cash dispenser machines, using Micro Focus Cobol and Net- MB Operating System (PROCOMP)
- Y2K: AB system conversion for turn of millennium

INTERESTS

I'm looking for a remote job opportunity in web application development (Django/Flask/React). Availability: 4h/day

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Rilson Barros de Almeida, born at 1967/08/12, Brazilian, married, living on St.Jardim Federacao, 334 Edf. Barão de Rothschild/704 - Federacao - Salvador/BA - Brazil